Guide to the Thomas McMahon Correspondence
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Thomas McMahon correspondence
1945-1968
YCAL MSS 410
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.42
(1 box)
Letters to Thomas McMahon from various writers, poets, and editors, including Gertrude Buckman, James Laughlin, Adrienne Rich, Kurt Vonnegut, and Robert Penn Warren. Letters date from circa 1945-1968 and include a small amount of letters from unidentified correspondents.
McMahon, Thomas, 1922-1972
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Thomas McMahon, 1968.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Thomas McMahon
Thomas McMahon was born in New York City on October 28, 1922. He earned a bachelor's and master's degree from Yale University in 1948 and 1956, respectively. He was the founding editor of the Yale Poetry Review. McMahon taught at the University of Puerto Rico and joined the faculty of The University of Texas in 1970. McMahon published many articles on Ernest Hemingway and F. Scott Fitzgerald.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of letters to Thomas McMahon from various writers, poets, and editors, including Gertrude Buckman, James Laughlin, Adrienne Rich, Kurt Vonnegut, and Robert Penn Warren. Letters date from circa 1945-1968 and include a small amount of letters from unidentified correspondents.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century; Buckman, Gertrude; Laughlin, James, 1914-1997; McMahon, Thomas, 1922-1972; Rich, Adrienne, 1929-2012; Vonnegut, Kurt, 1922-2007; Warren, Robert Penn, 1905-1989
- Thomas McMahon Correspondence
  - Bill, Dan, 1957 July 15, undated (Box 1)
  - Botsford, Keith and Zhiva, 1963-1968 (Box 1)
  - Brooks, Cleanth, 1956-1958 (Box 1)
  - Buckman, Gertrude, undated (Box 1)
  - Bullock, Allan, 1964-1967 (Box 1)
  - Bunker, George, 1964-1968 (Box 1)
  - Collingwood, E. W., 1959 January 4 (Box 1)
  - Cuddehy, John, 1961 (Box 1)
  - De Vane, William, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Deakin, Bill, 1956-1957 (Box 1)
  - Deutsch, Babette, 1956-1963 (Box 1)
  - Fjelde, Rolf, 1965-1968 (Box 1)
  - Gardner, Helen, 1956-circa 1966 (Box 1)
  - Goldstein, Julius, circa 1961-1968 (Box 1)
  - Greene, Helga, 1954-1968 (Box 1)
  - Hamill, Pete, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Hunt, John C., 1962-1966 (Box 1)
  - Kennedy, Bill, 1966-1968 (Box 1)
  - Megnien, Joan, 1949-1950 (Box 1)
  - Miller, Mary, circa 1957 (Box 1)
  - Putnam, Clay, 1953-1954 (Box 1)
  - Reck, Michael, 1962-1967 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes 25 Christmas Haiku by Reck
  - Richardson, Larry, 1945-1946 (Box 1)
  - Saal, Hubert, 1965-1967 (Box 1)
  - Sanavio, Piero, 1965-1968 (Box 1)
    Includes clippings on literature
  - Sewall, Ditsy, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Shapiro, Harvey and Edna, 1947-1968 (Box 1)
    Includes typescript drafts of poems by Harvey Shapiro
  - Shatheck, Roger, 1946-1968 (Box 1)
  - Stephenson, Robert C., 1962-1966 (Box 1)
  - Warren, Robert Penn, 1949-1968 (Box 1)
  - Wilde, Pat, 1950-1951 (Box 1)
  - Wise, Bill, 1950-1953 (Box 1)
  - Yalfe, James, 1958-1965, undated (Box 1)
  - Unidentified correspondence, 1959-1968 (Box 1)